Proctor and why you felt really good
about him to to move back and take him
over.
>> Sure. Yeah, good question. Um, he's
unique. He's rare. Uh, he's a 350lb man
with unique athletic traits that can
play four spots across the line of line
of scrimmage, the left tackle, right
tackle, both guards. Um,
the athletic traits for a man his size
are through the roof. You know, I know
there's been some questions about his
weight. It's well documented. Obviously,
we were very aware. We did our due
diligence uh with our resources. We feel
really good about where he is at uh with
that. And um
we brought him in on a 30 visit. Uh I
could feel his conviction and his desire
to be a good football player and do the
things that he needs to do to be the
best pro that he can be. Um all I can
tell you is that
there wasn't another one in the draft
like him. period.
>> Do you envision him starting off at
tackle?
>> You know what I mean? That's I think I
think I I don't want to pigeon hole him.
We'll give them to the coaches and kind
of we we'll get the best five out there.
I do think he has the unique ability to
play all four spots at a really high
level. Um
it's hard to say. You know, we got some
other guys. Obviously, Brew is very, you
know, he's a center so that's but you
know, Pat Paul and then you had Jonah
and Jo, you know, who knows? Uh and then
and then Austin. We're excited about him
coming back healthy at right tackle. So,
we'll just do what we need to do to get
the best five out there. Uh the unique
thing about him is he can line up in all
those spots and you feel really good
about it.
>> There's always going to be second
guessing and wondering I think for
people on the direction you go when you
look at the situation where you had 11,
you had Caleb DS potentially there or a
guy like Ruben Bane, a local guy. How is
that process in real time as it's
happening or was it a situation where
you were set on Proctor regardless at
that point?
>> You know what, uh the other, you know,
Downs and Bane are marvelous players.
Um, and I understand the question and I
I think those guys will go on to be very
successful in this league. No doubt
about it. Again, we thought uh we
thought Proctor was was rare. His
height, weight, speed, production, the
things that he can do uh on the football
field for a man his size, he's an
outlier. There's there's there's not
many like him. Um that's it has, you
know, it's no shot at. Caleb D's a
phenomenal phenomenal football player
and he'll have a great career and we
would have loved to have him here, but
we had a lot of conviction on on Proctor
being a very unique player in this draft
and one that uh that that we can build
around for years. Um, you know, we
invested in Malik and it was important
for us to protect him to make sure that
he has time to do the things that he
needs to do uh and keep him healthy, you
know, so that was part of the
conversation as well. Um, so yeah, we uh
we're thrilled with the pick. We're
happy to add him. We have a lot of faith
in the person. Um and and we think he's
going to be a really good player here.
You know, no apologies.
>> You mentioned in the 30 visit that he
was impressed at how straight you guys
were. You said you guys were straight
shooters. What expectations did you guys
line out uh to him when you spoke with
him?
>> Yeah, it was more just a real honest
direct conversation with substance. You
know, we we we asked him to walk
>> us through his time at Bama, the lessons
he learned, the back and forth from
Iowa, the weight. Um, and he didn't hide
from any of it, you know, and he talked
about his growth and the things that he
learned through that journey. Um, and
then obviously we have our resources at
Bama who have been with him recently,
you know, over the last couple years
and, uh, and we have really good
relationships there and, you know,
things like competitive, prideful, uh,
never wants to be embarrassed, leads the
conditioning runs. Um, you know what I
can tell you about him is,
you know, I don't need to name name the
coach by name, but there was a coach
there at one point who was militant
about weights. Um, he didn't worry about
Proctor's weight. That wasn't an issue
for him because he could handle it. Um,
the guy's got 270 pounds of lean body
mass. You know, he's just a naturally
large human being. Um, but he's not a
fat guy, you know, and if if you put
your eyes on him when he gets around
here, you'll see that pretty quickly.
So, I say all to say, look, none of us
have a crystal ball. You don't know what
the future's going to bring. Uh, but we
feel really good about what we invested
in tonight as a as a human being, as a
professional, and as a football player.
>> So, you said last week that you guys run
through simulations of how the draft
could go. How many scenarios did Kaden
fall to you guys at 11? Um, most to be
honest with you, most we were good with
that. Uh, now there were some teams that
were trying to move up. You know, I'll
keep those teams to myself, but there
were some teams trying to move up and we
felt pretty good, uh, at least about one
of them, uh, coming to get him. So, um,
you know, we're excited about how this
night ended. Um, you know, it was an
organizational decision. Our coaches
loved him, our scouts loved him. All the
analytics told you this guy's a unique,
rare guy. Um, so I, you know, again, I
can't, uh, I understand the questions
and, you know, that's just the way this
business goes. Like, whoever you pick,
you know, you guys are going to have
questions about why you didn't do this
and why you didn't do that, and that's
okay. You got a job to do. Understand
that. Not mad at you for it. Um, but
just know we feel really good about who
we invested in tonight. Flipping to the
other side of the ball, um what stood
out to you about Chris Johnson and how
did you evaluate, you know, the Mountain
West play versus some of the other guys
that play SEC, Big 10, etc., etc.
>> Yeah, you know, when you watch Chris,
he's got great feet, great balance and
body control. He's physical. He's a big
corner. He can play nickel, play outside
corner. He's got ball skills. I mean,
when you start checking the boxes for a
defensive back, there wasn't really
left. there were there weren't really
many left. Uh there were none really.
He'll tackle, you know, he's again
physical. Um he's just got and he's got
upside. He's 21 years old. He's a good
kid. He handles his business. He works.
He wants to be a good player. Um he's
about the right stuff. He's the kind of
guy that we want to infuse into this uh
into this locker room as is Proctor. You
know, those guys are football's
important to them and uh and they both
have edge. You know, they have edge to
them. Uh they both in a good way reek of
confidence, not arrogance, but
confidence. You know, they think they're
players and all those things were
important to us as we build this thing
out.
>> For a second, you you said that most
scenarios he was going to fall to you.
What did you guys value in him then that
other team might not have? What you see
that you said he's going to work here?
>> You want me to go through it again?
>> No, no, no. But you said most most
scenarios had him fallen to you. Sure.
>> And two two tackles were taken right
before you.
>> Yeah.
>> Um why what did you guys value that?
>> Why do you think you valued them and
other teams didn't?
>> I don't think that other teams didn't
value him. Like I said, I know one team
in particular was trying to come up to
our spot to get them. Um and there there
was another that was calling and I have
a pretty good, you know, pretty good
sense that they were too. You I can't
speak for the other 31 teams. I wouldn't
even pretend to do that uh to be able to
do that. But, you know, again, the
things that we valued were the size, the
athleticism, the ability to play bully
ball. You know, all the things I stated.
You know, you can't play through him.
He's hard to play around. He could play
four spots. He's versatile. Um, we just
felt like he was a a unique player.
>> You stayed at 11. Would it still have
been Proctor or was would Downs have
been the guy?
>> Proctor.
>> Yeah. So, you said last week you'd
rather have two good players than one
special one in terms of whether you
wanted to trade up or down. What was it
about Chris Johnson specifically that
you said we need to trade up?
>> I think it was the versatility and I
think it was the upside. You know, we
feel like he's really gifted. Uh he's
young. Like I said, he's 21. We feel
like, you know, he can play really uh,
you know, he'll play nickel or he'll
play corner, but we also feel like, you
know, depending on how this thing goes
over, he he'd go back there and play
safety as well because of the ball
skills and the instincts. I don't think
we'd end up doing that. He's going to
play a corner, play nickel. Um, but we
just we had a lot of conviction on him.
We got a lot of picks. We felt like we
had the flexibility to do that because
of some of the draft capital that we
had. And we stayed whole, you know, we
didn't we didn't we swapped. We didn't
lose. you know, we started the day with
11, we got 11 now. So, felt like it was
the right thing to do.
>> You've gone over some of the individual
qualities of the players that you
selected. Um, in the bigger picture, can
you talk about the trenches with with
Proctor and getting a cornerback, which
you needed, and and you know, starting
off the defense uh with with a corner.
>> Sure. I'm sorry. Just say that again.
Um, talk about building the trenches,
which you said is a priority with
Proctor and then with with Chris
Johnson, you know, you get a cornerback
to to kind of build the secondary.
>> Sure.
>> Yeah. I mean, it just you follow the
board, you know? I mean, you always want
to you if you can help it, I think you
always, at least the way I was taught in
this thing, you want to build it from
the inside out, but you're not going to
reach on guys. You got to follow the
board. And we felt like, you know, the
way the board was sitting at the time
when Chris was there, um, he was he was
we felt for us he was the best player
available. And and again, it's, you
know, you guys know how this thing goes.
It's it's subjective. You know, you do
all the work in the that you can. You
got your analytics, you got your
coaches, you got your personnel staff.
Um, and you do you do that for a reason.
Uh, and when you have conviction on a on
a player, organizational conviction, uh,
I think you have to listen to that.
That's why that's why you go through the
process and and he was one that we had
that kind of conviction on and uh and so
we do what we did.
>> You said the word conviction a a lot as
this is your first war room with this
team as the GM. What was that process
like as the voices in there and and and
getting to that point where you were all
in alignment to make these couple of
picks? Like what was that process like?
>> Sure. Just a you know a lot of work by a
lot of people as you well know. Um, and
then a lot of conversations, you know,
we we have, you know, we have multiple
meetings, um, you know, throughout the
month of April, throughout the month of
March. Uh, we have February draft
meetings, but we keep it all separate
because we're trying to identify the
outliers. That's the way we do it. I
don't want group think. I'm I'm trying
to eliminate bias, which can happen when
you have everybody in the room doing it
at one time. Um, these two guys, to be
perfectly honest with you, we didn't
have we never had there were no
outliers. We were convicted on these
guys. You know, the analytics did it
here, coaches did it here, we did it
here, and then we brought it together
and we looked at it. We were aligned
from the jump on these guys. We saw it
the same. And I told you before, like,
you know, I don't need the validation of
alignment all the time, but it helps,
you know, it helps for for a healthy
organization. You know, at the end of
the day, the buck stops with me. I take
responsibility for every player we pick,
whether it turns out the way you want it
to or whether it goes south. uh it stops
with me. I'm not hiding from it. I
really like what we did tonight and uh
you know it's the bottom line.
>> In the case of Chris Johnson, how
important was his performance at the
combine toward either getting your eyes
focused on him or solidifying what you
already knew? No,
>> it's a great question and be honest with
you is very important. Uh somebody
mentioned the conference he plays in,
you know, you know what I mean? I think
at the end of the day, you're always
looking for traits, right? I told you
guys before, at least in my mind, this
this this game at this level is played
by men with traits, you know, and he you
watched him play in in the fall and he
had all the he had the feet, he had the
balance, he's instinctive, he has all
those things, ball skills, but then
you're like, "All right, I want to see
how he measures up with those corners in
the SEC and he ran real fast and he
jumped real high and all of a sudden
you're going, "All right, you got a 6
foot plus 193 pound corner nickel that
can play three, four spots that ran ran
fast, jumped high, broad, you know, all
of it. And it just helps you come to a
conclusion that, yeah, this guy's
exactly what I think he is. Not only is
the film really good, not only is the
upside really good, but all the traits
in the world that uh that that you could
want in a in a in a guy who has to cover
players at this level, he's got them.
He's got recovery speed. Uh he's got
short area quickness. Um all those
things, you know, it shows itself on
tape, but then he validated it at the
combine, which gives you peace of mind.
trades with both picks. Uh what was all
the wheelie and wheeling uh high level
of activity like for you and what do you
think of what you got out of those
trades aside from the players?
>> Yeah, I mean I think the fact that you
know I've already shared with you how we
felt about Proctor and he was kind of
our guy. Um, so yeah, to come out it
with with with two extra picks and not
really, you know, just free money, you
know. Um, so, you know, feel really good
about it, you know, and then to go up
and get a guy in Chris that we had a lot
of conviction on and not lose a pick,
you know, still stay whole. Feel good
about it.
>> So, what was
>> last week? You were up here and you
mentioned that you had a dream. You woke
up to a couple names off the board. Uh
curious if either of these two players
were one of those guys.
>> You know what? I I'll keep the names to
myself that they weren't and and I you
know for full transparency I think I
must have been back in Green Bay because
I was actually pulling a tag off the
board and we have digital here.
Everything's digital. So uh but uh um no
it wasn't one of the two. But uh I think
it just tells you about the excitement
you know that that I had that we had.
Uh, we've been talking about this day,
spent a lot of time in the draft room,
hours upon hours trying to get to this
point and prepare. And, uh, you know,
we're excited. We feel like it was a
really good first day. But, uh, it's,
uh, it was, it was a funny dream. I was
pulling the tag and I I literally woke
up and I thought to myself like, damn, I
was in Green Bay.
It wasn't digital.
>> Almost kind of building off of that
question, what was this day like for you
leading up to the start of the first
round? You know, first do you have a
post note in your pocket said Kaden
Proctor no matter what or
>> No, you know, you you have all that time
on the front end of the day. You know,
it's like the day itself takes a month,
you know, to finally get to 8:00. But,
uh,
for me, I just I think sometimes you
just go back to the simplicity of
everything. You know, you read through
your notes, you look at the great you
look, how do I feel about him? How do
our coaches feel about him? How do our
scouts that do a great job feel about
them? and you know, you start weighing
things out and and it it speaks to you.
It talks to you. And look, man, there's
there's a lot of other really good
players that were on the board um that
are still on the board. Uh but that's
this business. You got to make
decisions. Um and uh feel good about the
ones we made today.
>> For the record, just asking like your
nerves, the calmness of it, like what
went through your brain as you're
preparing for this? Yeah, it was I mean
I I came in, we met with our guys, uh I
got a workout in which helped me kind of
clear my head and then uh I mean and
this is this is just the truth of it.
There there was an eerie calm for me
like it's the work is done like this is
the fun part. Now that doesn't mean you
know things can heat up and go you know
in moments when trades are happening
things get going fast but you stay calm
and you communicate and you and you you
know you do what you need to do for your
team. It's the execution piece of it.
The work is in and has been done and
it's like there there was a calm that
came with the preparation. Uh which was
I didn't expect it. It was pretty cool
to be honest with you. I kind of I told
somebody beforehand like I you know
there's a like I feel like I should be
more anxious. I'm not. I trust the
people in the room. I trust our work. I
trust the process. And uh like I said, I
think the Dolphins got better today.
I'm reading a quote here from the
athletics uh scouting guide from a NFL
scout who said that Chris Johnson's give
a damn factor to the moon. Leader of the
DB room, likable kid. His parents did an
amazing job. I was just curious to get
your perspective on your guys'
background with Chris Johnson.
>> Yeah, everything you just said, you
know, we did a lot of work on him like
we do on all the players. Um the coaches
San Diego State couldn't have said
better things about him. His care factor
is high. He was a captain, team captain
there. He's a leader. Uh he works. Um
the intangibles
along with the athletic traits along
with the fact that he's a good football
player lead to the conviction
why we did what we did. You know that's
uh you know I I told you guys from the
jump you know um it's important that we
we had the right kind of people here and
Proctor's in that I mean you know he
didn't hide from it and he's we feel
like he's going this way and so do the
people who've been around him you know
over the last couple years. Um, these
these are young people. Young people
make mistakes. They have bumps in the
roads. If I peel the layers back on all
you guys when you were young, I know I
made my mistakes. I'm sure y'all did,
too. These kids aren't any different,
you know? They're no different, you
know, and they and they deserve, you
can't bury them because they stubbed
their toe along the way. I mean, there's
certain things you won't forgive, but a
guy who's, you know, battled his weight
a little bit here and there and has
gotten together and played really good
football, you know, you got to give guys
their due and see where they're going,
not where they've been all the time in
my opinion.
>> I heard a coach say the other day that
your first round pick or first round
picks in your case are supposed to
change the tone of practice. How do you
I don't know if you I don't know if you
subscribe to that, but how do you
believe these two guys kind of change
the the tone of practice?
>> Sure. Um you know, I I think with
Proctor when he walks out there, he's
going to change the tone of practice. uh
just with his size and his mass and I I
think when when when you see people try
to when they run into him and he you
know the stopping power that he has, the
ability to move uh large men coming off
the ball in the run game um you know
that'll speak for itself, you know. Um,
and again, I I just I think the
I think the raw athleticism of of of
Johnson and again his ability to be
versatile uh with his athletic traits
and his mental, you know, smarts, you
know, I think I think they'll recogn I
think the team will recognize that
pretty quick and respect it. You know,
that's what I would say.
>> So, as you look
>> as you look to day two, is it still best
player available or do you feel some
needs?
>> No, it's uh need comes into play. Hey, I
mean, we'll always follow the board in
terms of value, but you know, if you're
looking at two guys that have the same
value and and and you need one more,
then it comes into play. That makes
sense, you know. Um,
got to, you know, yes, there there there
do there does come a point where you're
trying to fill holes, but you're not
going to not follow the value of the
board.
>> There's obviously high expectations, you
know, obviously based on what you said
about Parker. How much do you have to
help him understand and not this
conversation from the outside get to his
head and put even more pressure on him
to perform?
>> Yeah, you know, I mean,
it's a good question. I think part part
of it when you when you when you draft
these guys, you have faith in our I have
faith in our building and the people in
this building. I have faith in Coach
Hafley. I have faith in Coach Yenszer.
have faith in, you know, our
nutritionists and our strength staff and
all the people that come to work here
every day that are really good at their
job. Um, you know, every I said this to
our the first and I hate to use the word
speech, but the first talk I gave to the
building, like we all have a job to do
and nobody here is more important than
the other. Like we all have a role in
this thing to get this place where we
need it to get to. Um, and that's part
of it. Like that's why you have a
building full of people that have
different jobs is to help these players
be the best that they can be. And I have
a lot of faith in this building and the
people that come to work here every day.
I also have faith in him that he's going
to do the things that he needs to do. So
um you know and he's been at Bama, you
know what I mean? He's been at Bama and
he's been out there every week playing
uh you know he lined up every you know
every Saturday and played good ball. You
know go watch the tape. I mean it's
that's you know I'll sit down and watch
the tape with any of you if you want to.
You tell me.
>> Is that an opening business?
>> Yeah, I was about to say
>> at some point tomorrow.
>> All right, y'all have a good night. See
you. Take it easy.